<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="arduino_boards">Arduino Boards</string>

    <string name="input_1">Input 1</string>
    <string name="input_2">Input 2</string>
    <string name="input_3">Input 3</string>
    <string name="voltage">Voltage</string>
    <string name="current">Current</string>
    <string name="resistance">Resistance</string>
    <string name="gyr_x">Gyroscope X</string>
    <string name="gyr_y">Gyroscope Y</string>
    <string name="gyr_z">Gyroscope Z</string>

    <string name="temperature">Temperature</string>
    <string name="temperature_c_units">\u00B0C</string>
    <string name="temperature_f_units">\u00B0F</string>
    <string name="current_units">A</string>
    <string name="resistance_units">k\u03A9</string>
    <string name="gyr_units">\u00B0/s</string>

    <string name="pressure">Pressure</string>
    <string name="pressure_units">atm</string>
    <string name="humidity">Humidity</string>
    <string name="humidity_units">%</string>
    <string name="proximity">Proximity</string>
    <string name="proximity_units">%</string>
    <string name="color_ambient_light">Ambient Light</string>
    <string name="color_ambient_light_units">lux</string>
    <string name="color_temperature">Color Temperature</string>
    <string name="color_temperature_units">K</string>

    <string name="mkrsci_input_sensor_raw">Raw</string>
    <string name="mkrsci_input_sensor_temperature_c">Temperature (Celsius)</string>
    <string name="mkrsci_input_sensor_temperature_f">Temperature (Fahrenheit)</string>
    <string name="mkrsci_input_sensor_light">Light</string>

    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_acc">A device that measures acceleration</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_current">The amount of flow of charged particles between two places</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_gyr">A device that measures orientation and angular velocity (rotation).</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_magnetometer">An instrument used to measure the intensity and direction of a magnetic field</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_resistance">The measure of the difficulty of current flow through an object or material</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_voltage">The difference in electric potential between two places that allows a current to flow</string>

    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_temperature">Ambient temperature in C or F</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_pressure">A barometric sensor is used to measure air pressure in a certain environment. Air Pressure can impact short term changes in the weather. The Barometric Air Pressure is measured in Atmosphere or atm.</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_humidity">A humidity sensor is an electronic device that measures the humidity in its environment and converts it into an electrical signal. Relative humidity is measured in %.</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_color_illuminance">The ambient light sensor measures light in lux, a measure of illumination that depends on the amount of incoming light and the area over which it is spread. The amount of light is measured in lux.</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_color_temperature">Color temperature is a characteristic of visible light that has important applications in many industries, such as: lighting, photography, astrophysics, manufacturing, and other fields. Color temperature is expressed in Kelvins (K), a unit of measurement for absolute temperature.</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_color_temperature_p2">The CIE 1931 x,y chromaticity space, also showing the chromaticities of black-body light sources of various temperatures (Planckian locus), and lines of constant correlated color temperature.</string>
    <string name="sensor_desc_short_mkrsci_proximity">A proximity sensor is a sensor able to detect the presence of nearby objects without any physical contact. A proximity sensor often emits an electromagnetic field or a beam of electromagnetic radiation (infrared, for instance), and looks for changes in the field or return signal. The object being sensed is often referred to as the proximity sensor\'s target. Proximity here is measured in millimeters or mm.</string>

    <string name="terms">Terms of Services</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy Policy</string>

    <string name="get_started_header_location">Location</string>
    <string name="get_started_action_understand">I understand</string>
    <string name="get_started_header_done">That’s it!</string>
    <string name="get_started_message_done">We’re done checking for permissions. If you need to modify these permissions in the future, you can do so at any time in the Science Journal app settings of the Android Settings app.</string>
    <string name="get_started_action_done">Continue</string>

    <string name="first_experiment_note_1">Shape your future! Reason with data and think like a real scientist! Turn your phone into a pocket science laboratory with tools to measure light, motion, sound and more!</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_2">Arduino Science Journal is a digital science journal that you can use to document projects through notes, photos, and your phones\'s built-in sensors, as well as external boards.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_3">To create a new experiment, click on the + in the bottom of the Arduino Science Journal app home screen. Then click on the pencil icon in the top to give your experiment a good name!</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_4">The observation toolbar in the app can help you record the data around you. Let’s take a look!</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_5">To start exploring your world by measuring light, sound, movement, and more, tap the Sensor button.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_6">You can manage your sensors in the Sensor settings screen. Go back to the sensor tab in the toolbar and tap the Gear icon on the sensor card.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_7">You can add notes and hypotheses to your experiments by tapping the Note icon.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_8">To make note of a single sensor measurement, tap the Snapshot Sensor button. You can also record sensor data over time, select a sensor and press the Record button to start capturing data.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_9">Add camera shots, notes and photos to keep track of your observations while recording.</string>
    <string name="first_experiment_note_10">Find activities to try at science-journal.arduino.cc\n\nNow that you know the basics of using Arduino Science Journal, you can use it to conduct experiments and explore your world!</string>

</resources>
